PRIYA BALI

Antioch, CA | (925) 305-4616 | priya.bali24@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented IT Support Specialist with the key ability of building and strengthening client relationships through exceptional, professional, and personable technical service delivery. Well-versed in both on-site and remote support provisioning. Excels at rapidly and reliably identifying hardware or software weaknesses for remediation through quick and cost-effective means. Practiced troubleshooter with excellent diagnostics and repair abilities, strong attention to detail, and methodical approach. Skilled at establishing priorities to complete tasks within scheduled time frames. Effectively communicates with technical and non-technical audiences, both verbally and written. Excellent customer service and interpersonal skills with the ability to interact with stakeholders at all levels. Established reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS

Windows 7/8/10 Desktop and Laptop Support – Desktop/Laptop Migration – Setting up Routers and Switches Desktop Ticketing Systems – TCP/IP Networking – Neighbor Discovery via CDP and LLDP – IP Connectivity Routing Protocols: Dynamic (OSPF, EIGRP, BGP) and Static Routing – Configuration of VLAN and VTP Protocol Inter-VLAN Routing – WAN services: MetroE, MPLS, Internet VPNs via IPsec – DNS, DHCP, FTP, TFTP – Mac OS Windows Server: Active Directories, Objects, Hyper-V, DNS, DHCP, Group Policies, Domains – Windows OS Authentication of Users (Local and RADIUS) – Configuration of NAT – Securing Network Techniques Network Automation and Controller-Based Networking (Cisco DNAC) – Forest & Domains – Wireless LAN Cisco IOS commands and Devices' Configurations – Microsoft Office Suite – Windows Server Installation Wireless AP: Autonomous and Lightweight – End User Support – Mobile Device Support (IOS and Android)

EDUCATION

Certificate of Achievement in Network Technology Fundamentals

Diablo Valley College | Pleasant Hill, CA | 2019 – 2020

GPA: 4/4

Master of Technology in VLSI Design

Thapar University | India | 2014 – 2016

CGPA: 7.4/10

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering

Chitkara Institute of Engineering & Technology | India | 2009 – 2013

Percentage: 75%

CERTIFICATIONS

CCNA 200-301 Certified CSCO13645410

Introduction to Networks Provided by Cisco Netacad

Switching Routing and Wireless Essential by Cisco Netacad

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Windows Server

DIABLO VALLEY COLLEGE | Pleasant Hill, CA | 08/2020 – 12/2020

Installed, configured, and supported Microsoft technology solutions on Windows platform hosting web and database applications, while maintaining security patches, antivirus updates, backups, monitoring and performing routine server maintenance.

Performed Virtual Machine (VM) administrative duties including creating Gen1 and Gen2 VMs, joining VMS
to their domains, creating Snapshots, and troubleshooting problems in the Virtual Machine settings level.

- Devised solutions to operations issues related to Windows, working closely via phone, email, live chat and web teleconference.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Led the installation of Hyper-V via Add Roles and Features.
- Oversaw the installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of Active Directory Domain Services.
- Spearheaded the creation of DHCP Scopes and AD Objects including organizational units, groups (local, global, universal), and users.
- Ensured network security by modifying Firewall rules and putting security on folders, including NTFS permissions and shared permissions.

Lab Assistant

DIABLO VALLEY COLLEGE | Pleasant Hill, CA | 2019 – 2020

Administered, developed, and implemented comprehensive server-based information technology systems under the supervision of the Professor.

- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for students, prepared and installed PCs and printers.
- Installed, tested, troubleshot, and maintained all networking devices and infrastructure including switches, routers, and firewalls.
- Defined security requirements for computer systems, including mainframe, workstations, and personal computers.
- Verified system functionality and backup for network-related equipment.
- Diagnosed system hardware and software problems using advanced root-cause analysis.
- Assisted Professor in lab classes to aid students with their work on network devices (Routers and Switches).
- Utilized VMware, Active Directories, Image installations, DNS and DHCP Scopes in Windows 2019 server.

Teacher Assistant

THAPAR UNIVERSITY | India | 2014 - 2016

Worked in conjunction with the Professor on the planning and implementation of course material; effectively assisted and taught students while building positive relationships.

- Utilized knowledge of MATLAB and VHDL to assist junior students in lab environment.
- Observed students' performance and recorded relevant data to assess progress.
- Supported instructor with test administration, curriculum development and assignment grading.
- Guided students through problems and concepts by working one-on-one with students and providing hands-on demonstrations.

Intern in Networking

NETMAX TECHNOLOGIES PRIVATE LIMITED | India | 01/2012 – 07/2012

- Configured routers and switches (2900 Series) and learned Remote Access via Telnet, SSH.
- Trained for LANs, VLANs, and authenticating users locally.
- Trained for IP Addresses: IPv4 and IPv6, Subnetting in IPv4.
- Trained for NAT to get access to outside networks via public IP addresses.
- Successfully completed a project in which LANs were created in metropolitan areas and connected using Routing Protocols

SKILLS

Interpersonal Communication – Customer Service – Active Listening – Improving Customer Experience – Patience Building Customer Loyalty – Complaint Resolution – Leadership – Trilingual (English, Hindi, Punjabi) – Positivity Planning – Critical Thinking – Staff Training & Development – Teamwork – Multitasking – Time Management